Anthony Chau Frias

Android Developer

Chiclayo, Peru (GMT-5) (+51) 978897878 anthonysy21@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/anthonychaufrias

Passionate Android developer about creating native apps with 4+ years of experience using Java. One of my greatest achievements was to speed up to 70% of the reports of an educational institution's web system "Finanzas del alumno". What I am looking for in a company is to continue growing professionally, learning new things, and putting them into practice.

EXPERIENCE

TicSolu, Android and Web Developer — November, 2019 - March, 2020

- Developed a web app for the sale and stock management of mobile devices.
- Developed the mobile version of this software, an **Android app** with the same features.
- Integrated both **applications** with the Firebase services.

Tech Stack: Java(Android), Javascript, AngularJS, Firebase Authentication, Firebase Realtime Database

La Canastita, Android Developer — February, 2018 - August, 2018

• Participated in the development of an E-commerce application for **android mobile** devices, improving by 40% the requests to the back-end, adding a security layer and token validations.

Tech Stack: Java(Android), XML, PHP5, MySQL

TicSolu, Software Developer — *April, 2017 - December, 2017*

- Improved the management and lifetime of the piling machines by up to 20% by developing the "Rice Piling Scheduling" functionality, depending on the available schedule, customer priority, the quantity of rice bags and availability of the piling machine.
- Developed a **mobile app** to allow customers to visualize the piling status of their rice bags. This increased the customer's trust in the Company(mill).
- Implemented the back-end, which was oriented to support the requests coming from the mobile app.

Tech Stack: Java(Android), XML, PHP5, JQuery, JavaScript, MySQL

PROJECTS

People, GitHub Repository — https://bit.ly/github-people — 2022

• Built a **repository on GitHub** about Kotlin. This is a CRUD template so any developer could build their own projects based on this example.

Tech Stack: Kotlin, Git, GitHub, MVVM, Clean Architecture, Dagger Hilt

Snack, Android App for Food Delivery— https://bit.ly/deliverysnack — 2020 - 2022

Built an Android app to satisfy the services of Food Delivery, and Order and Pick up Food. I integrated this app with
Firebase Authentication, Google Maps, Firebase Cloud Messaging, Firebase Realtime Database, and Google Cloud
services.

Tech Stack: Java(Android), Kotlin, XML, MySQL, PHP7, Google Play Console, Firebase, Google Cloud, Google Search Console

FastMind, Indie Videogame — http://bit.ly/fastmindgame — 2014 - 2019

• Created my first videogame, a personal project of which I am very proud because I was able to reach the final round in the "Indie Prize PERÚ2019 LITE" contest and from which I learned a lot since I experienced all the stages for this project. I integrated this game with Google Play Games Services to manage the leaderboards and achievements.

<u>Tech Stack</u>: **Java(Android)**, XML, Fireworks, **Google** Play Games Services, **Google** Play Services, **Google** Play Console, Google Cloud

SKILLS

Programming Languages: Advanced: Java, PHP, PLSQL; Intermediate: JavaScript, C#, TypeScript

Frameworks and Tools: Advanced: JQuery, AngularJS, Android Studio, Postman; Intermediate: Angular, Laravel, VS Code.

Databases: Advanced: MySQL, SQL Server; Intermediate: PostgreSQL, Oracle Database; Basic: MongoDB.

Languages: Intermediate: English; Native: Spanish.

EDUCATION

'Pedro Ruiz Gallo' National University – Lambayeque, Peru. *Bachelor's degree, Systems Engineering, September 2013*

CERTIFICATIONS

Introduction to videogame design – Miríadax. 2017.

Programming Mobile Applications for Android Handheld Systems – Coursera. 2014.

Creative, Serious and Playful Science of Android Apps – Coursera. 2014.

Being more creative – Coursera. 2013.